Guide to the Richard Charles Lee Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Photographs, 1947-1969; Series V
  - Mayor Lee at top of garage, 1966 (Box 144, Folder 2489)
  - "The Mayor and the Changing City": (correspondence and negative for cover), 1966 (Box 144, Folder 2490)
  - "The Mayor and the Changing City": lay outs, 1966 (Box 144, Folder 2491-2492)
  - "The Mayor and the Changing City": negatives, 1966 (Box 144, Folder 2493)
  - Miscellaneous, 1967 January - February (Box 144, Folder 2494)
  - Miscellaneous and Ad Club Award Dinner, 1967 March (Box 144, Folder 2495)
  - Miscellaneous, 1967 March (Box 144, Folder 2496)
  - Chapel Square Mall opening, 1967 April (Box 144, Folder 2497)
  - Chapel Square Mall opening and Yale School Alumni speech, 1967 April (Box 144, Folder 2498)
  - Miscellaneous, 1967 May - June (Box 144, Folder 2499-2500)
  - Slides: Police Department boat dedication, 1967 June (Box 144, Folder 2501)
  - Police Boat dedication, 1967 June (Box 144, Folder 2502-2504)
  - Police Boat dedication and Mayor Lee with Secretary, 1967 July (Box 144, Folder 2505)
  - Miscellaneous, 1967 August (Box 144, Folder 2506)
  - Miscellaneous and groundbreaking: Trade Union Plaza, 1967 September (Box 144, Folder 2507)
  - Groundbreaking: Trade Union Plaza, 1967 September (Box 144, Folder 2508)
  - Portraits: slides, 1967 October (Box 144, Folder 2509)
  - Miscellaneous, 1967 October (Box 144, Folder 2510)
  - New Haven photographs, 1967 (Box 144, Folder 2511-2512)
  - Citizens Action Committee luncheon, 1968 March (Box 144, Folder 2513)
  - Groundbreaking for Dixwell Plaza, 1968 June (Box 144, Folder 2514)
  - Lee High School graduation and a ceremony, 1968 June (Box 145, Folder 2512)
  - Ceremony, 1968 June (Box 145, Folder 2516)
  - Mayor Lee and Mayor Chichung, 1968 July (Box 145, Folder 2517)
  - Proclamation signing and Veterans Day, 1968 August - November (Box 145, Folder 2518)
  - Miscellaneous, 1969 May - November (Box 145, Folder 2519)
  - International Headquarters of Knights of Columbus, 1969 (Box 145, Folder 2520-2521)
  - 10 Academy Street (Restoration), undated (Box 145, Folder 2522-2524)
  - Court Street in Wooster Square (Restoration), undated (Box 145, Folder 2525-2526)
  - Greene Street (Restoration), undated (Box 145, Folder 2527-2528)
  - Historic preservation and restoration, undated (Box 145, Folder 2529-2530)
  - Model View of Knights of Columbus adquarters and Coliseum (1st half-2nd half), undated (Box 145, Folder 2531-2533)
  - Oliver B. North House, 604 Chapel Street, undated (Box 145, Folder 2534-2535)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 145, Folder 2536-2542)
- Post-Mayoral Files, 1970-1983; Series VI
  2 linear feet (5 boxes)
  This series includes orrespondence, reports, speeches, and other materials. The series provides some documentation for the activities of Mayor Lee after he left office. There is, for example, information on his consulting activities, on addresses to classes and civic associations, and on awards and positions held since 1969. The series also contains copies of speeches and eulogies and copies of the materials Lee used when he was a Visiting Professor of Political Science at The University of Connecticut in the spring of 1971. This series is arranged chronologically by year and then alphabetically by subject or person.
  - 1970
    - "A" general (Box 146, Folder 2543)
    - "B" general (Box 146, Folder 2544)
    - Baltimore Urban Affairs Seminar (Box 146, Folder 2545)
    - Berman, Harry: Farewell (Box 146, Folder 2546)
    - Blackstone Associates (Box 146, Folder 2547)
    - "C" general (Box 146, Folder 2548)
    - Cincinnati trip (Box 146, Folder 2549)
    - "D" general (Box 146, Folder 2550)
    - Daley Book Review (Box 146, Folder 2551)
    - Duffy Dinner (Box 146, Folder 2552)
    - "E" general (Box 146, Folder 2553)
    - "F" general (Box 146, Folder 2554)
    - "G" general (Box 146, Folder 2555)
    - Guida, Bartholomew: inauguration (Box 146, Folder 2556)
    - "H" general (Box 146, Folder 2557)
    - Jackson, John Day (Box 146, Folder 2558)
    - "K" general (Box 146, Folder 2559)
    - "L" general (Box 146, Folder 2560)
    - Lamar, L. Q. C. Society: symposium (Box 146, Folder 2561)
    - "M" general (Box 146, Folder 2562)
    - "N" general (Box 146, Folder 2563)
    - "O" general (Box 146, Folder 2564)
    - "P" general (Box 146, Folder 2565)
    - Police Foundation (Box 146, Folder 2566-2567)
    - Police Foundation (Box 147, Folder 2568)
    - Project Concern (Box 147, Folder 2569)
    - "Q" general (Box 147, Folder 2570)
    - "R" general (Box 147, Folder 2571)
    - "S" general (Box 147, Folder 2572)
    - Speeches: 50th anniversary of the Junior League (Box 147, Folder 2573)
    - Speeches: dinner in Honor of the Late President J. F. Kennedy (Box 147, Folder 2574)
    - Speeches: testimonial to Sister Louise Anthony (Box 147, Folder 2575)
    - Speeches: Greater Baltimore Seminar (Box 147, Folder 2576)
    - "T" general (Box 147, Folder 2577)
    - "U" general (Box 147, Folder 2578)
    - United States Conference of Mayors (Box 147, Folder 2579)
    - The University of Connecticut (Box 147, Folder 2580)
    - University of Florida (Box 147, Folder 2581)
    - "V" general (Box 147, Folder 2582)
    - "W" general (Box 147, Folder 2583)
    - "Y" general (Box 147, Folder 2584)
    - Yale University (Box 147, Folder 2585)
    - Yale University: urban studies (Box 147, Folder 2586)
    - "Z" general (Box 147, Folder 2587)
  - 1971
    - "A" general (Box 147, Folder 2588)
    - Advertising Club: Gold Medal Award Winner (Box 147, Folder 2589)
    - "B" general (Box 147, Folder 2590)
    - Book Review (Box 147, Folder 2591)
    - "C" general (Box 147, Folder 2592)
    - "D" general (Box 147, Folder 2593)
    - Daley book review (Box 147, Folder 2594)
    - Duffy dinner (Box 148, Folder 2595)
    - "E" general (Box 148, Folder 2596)
    - "F" general (Box 148, Folder 2597)
    - Ford Motor Company (Box 148, Folder 2598)
    - "G" general (Box 148, Folder 2599)
    - "H" general (Box 148, Folder 2600)
    - Holden, Reuben: dinner (Box 148, Folder 2601)
    - "I" general (Box 148, Folder 2602)
    - "K" general (Box 148, Folder 2603)
    - "L" general (Box 148, Folder 2604)
    - Lamar, L. Q. C. Society: symposium (Box 148, Folder 2605-2606)
    - "M" general (Box 148, Folder 2607)
    - "N" general (Box 148, Folder 2608)
    - "O" general (Box 148, Folder 2609)
    - "P" general (Box 148, Folder 2610)
    - Police Foundation (Box 148, Folder 2611)
    - "Q" general (Box 148, Folder 2612)
    - "R" general (Box 148, Folder 2613)
    - "S" general (Box 148, Folder 2614)
    - Speeches: Advertising Club (Box 148, Folder 2615)
    - Speeches: L. Q. C. Lamar Society (Box 148, Folder 2616)
    - Speeches: "Urban Problems: The City" (Box 148, Folder 2617)
    - Speeches: "Books Sandwiched In" (Box 148, Folder 2618)
    - Speeches: Legislative Dinner Quinnipiac College (Box 148, Folder 2619)
    - "T" general (Box 148, Folder 2620)
    - United States Conference of Mayors (Box 148, Folder 2621-2622)
    - The University of Connecticut (Box 149, Folder 2623)
    - The University of Connecticut Raw Material (Box 149, Folder 2624)
    - Seminar: The University of Connecticut (Box 149, Folder 2625-2641)
    - University of Florida (Box 149, Folder 2642)
    - "W" general (Box 149, Folder 2643)
    - Yale University (Box 149, Folder 2644)
    - Yale University: Samuel Brownell (Box 149, Folder 2645)
    - Yale University: Urban Studies (Box 149, Folder 2646)
  - 1972
    - General (Box 149, Folder 2647)
    - Speeches: Greater Baltimore Urban Affairs Committee Speeches: (Box 149, Folder 2648)
    - Speeches: commencement Centenary College for Women (Box 149, Folder 2649)
    - Speeches: Grace - New Haven School of Nursing (Box 149, Folder 2650)
    - Speeches: address by the Honorable Constance Baker Motley, Quinnipiac College (Box 149, Folder 2651)
  - 1974
    - Architectural Forum (Box 149, Folder 2652)
    - Eulogy for Harry Berman (Box 149, Folder 2653)
  - 1976
    - Miscellaneous (Box 149, Folder 2654)
  - 1979
    - General (Box 149, Folder 2655)
    - Cosgrove, Daniel: roast (Box 149, Folder 2656)
    - Cosgrove, Daniel: testimonial (Box 149, Folder 2657)
    - Speeches (Box 149, Folder 2658)
    - United Way (Box 149, Folder 2659)
  - 1980
    - General (Box 150, Folder 2660)
    - Eulogy for Daniel De Angelis (Box 150, Folder 2661)
    - Eulogy for Charles Parker (Box 150, Folder 2662)
    - Speeches (Box 150, Folder 2663)
    - Speeches: by others. RE: retirement of Pastor of Saint Mary's Church (Box 150, Folder 2664)
  - 1981
    - Eulogy for Kennedy Mitchell (Box 150, Folder 2665)
    - Eulogy for Harry "Hobby" Turnbull (Box 150, Folder 2667)
  - 1982
    - Correspondence (Box 150, Folder 2668)
  - 1983
    - Correspondence (Box 150, Folder 2669-2671)
    - Speeches (Box 150, Folder 2672)
    - Miscellaneous, 1983 (Box 150, Folder 2673)
    - Speeches: "The Imitation of Mayor Daley" "A Cop May Throw the Book at You..." by William Marshall (Box 150, Folder 2674)
    - Sensitive restricted until 2045, 1983 (Box 151)
- Scrapbooks, 1947-1968; Series VII
  This series consists of ten reels of microfilm of forty-seven Lee scrapbooks. The scrapbooks contain useful information on New Haven and Connecticut politics, taken from New Haven and other area newspapers.
  MICROFILM HM 150. Lee, Richard Charles, 1916-, compiler. Scrapbooks of clippings chiefly relating to his political career in New Haven. 1947 Mar 26-1968 Dec 31, New Haven. 47 v. Microfilm. New Haven, Yale University Library, 1982. 10 reels.
  - Volume 1, 1947 March 26 - 1947 November 21
  - Volume 2, 1947 November 21 - 1948 April 1
  - Volume 3, 1948 April 1 - 1949 February 9
  - Volume 4, 1949 February 9 - 1949 July 15
  - Volume 5, 1949 July 17 - 1949 November 4
  - Volume 6, 1949 November 4 - 1950 March 12
  - Volume 7, 1950 March 12 - 1950 August 18
  - Volume 8, 1950 August 20 - 1951 January 17
  - Volume 9, 1951 January 17 - 1951 June 20
  - Volume 10, 1951 June 20 - 1951 October 15
  - Volume 11, 1951 October 11 - 1952 January 16
  - Volume 12, 1952 January 6 - 1952 July 6
  - Volume 13, 1952 July 7 - 1953 February 1
  - Volume 14, 1953 January 15 - 1953 August 16
  - Volume 15, 1953 August 16 - 1953 November 1
  - Volume 16, 1953 November 1 - 1953 December 31
  - Volume 17, 1953 November - 1955 February
  - Volume 18, 1954 January 1 - 1954 July 13
  - Volume 19, 1954 July 1 - 1954 December 31
  - Volume 20, 1955 January 2 - 1955 June 21
  - Volume 21, 1955 June 19 - 1956 January 3
  - Volume 22, 1956 January 1 - 1956 July 2
  - Volume 23, 1956 July 3 - 1956 December 31
  - Volume 24, 1957 January 2 - 1957 July 2
  - Volume 25, 1957 June 30 - 1957 December 31
  - Volume 26, 1958 January 1 - 1958 July 2
  - Volume 27, 1958 July 2 - 1958 December 31
  - Volume 28, 1959 January 1 - 1959 June 30
  - Volume 29, 1959 June 30 - 1959 December 31
  - Volume 30, 1960 January 1 - 1960 July 3
  - Volume 31, 1960 July 2 - 1960 December 31
  - Volume 32, 1961 January 1 - 1961 June 30
  - Volume 33, 1961 July 3 - 1961 December 31
  - Volume 34, 1962 January 1 - 1962 July 2
  - Volume 35, 1962 July 2 - 1962 December 31
  - Volume 36, 1963 January 1 - 1963 June 30
  - Volume 37, 1963 July 1 - 1963 December 31
  - Volume 38, 1964 January 1 - 1964 June 30
  - Volume 39, 1964 June 30 - 1964 December 31
  - Volume 40, 1965 January 1 - 1965 July 2
  - Volume 41, 1965 July 2 - 1965 December 31
  - Volume 42, 1966 January 1 - 1966 July 1
  - Volume 43, 1966 July 1- 1966 December 31
  - Volume 44, 1967 January 1 - 1967 July 1
  - Volume 45, 1967 July 1 - 1967 December 31
  - Volume 46, 1968 January 1 - 1968 July 24
  - Volume 47, 1968 July 18 - 1968 December 31
- Oversize Materials, 1950-1969
  - Posters, photographs, citations, 1958-1960 (Folder 152)
  - All-American City Award, 1958 (Folder 152)
  - Photographs
    - New Haven in Great Britain [album], undated (Box 153)
    - New Haven redevelopment, 1950s-1960s (Box 153)
    - "City Clean-Up Champion", article, 1966 January (Box 154)
    - New Haven redevelopment, 1958-1966 (Box 154)
    - New Haven Police and Fire Departments [second annual Communion breakfast, St. John the Baptist Church], 1956 February 26 (Box 154)
    - "The Island Nobody Knows," [redevelopment proposal for Blackwell's Island, New York City], 1969 (Box 154)
  - Publicity-advertising galley sheets, 1950s-1960s (Box 155)
- Additional Material, 1955-1967; Accession 1984-M-003
  - Richard C. Lee introducing Eleanor Roosevelt at Bonds for Israel Dinner, 1955 November 3; Audiotape (Reel-to-reel) (Box 1)
  - GOP Convention, 1961 August 14; 1; 7" acetate open reel audiotape. (Box 2–3)
  - Dedication (unidentified), 1967 June 4; Audiotape (Reel-to-reel) (Box 4)
  - Labor Rally, Senator Kennedy at Restland Farm, 1967 September 24; Audiotape (Reel-to-reel) (Box 5)
  - Unidentified, Undated; Audiotape (Reel to reel) (Box 6)
- Additional Material, Accession 1985-M-076
  - Campaign films
    - General (Box 1)
      - Texaco Huntley-Brinkley Report, Mayor Lee on Cities, 1961; Film reel (16mm) (Box 2.5)
        - Duplicating master, Videotape (Betacam-SP) (Box 2.5D)
        - Use copy, Videotape (VHS) (Box 2.5U)
    - Aerial New Haven, Oak Street, Legion Parade, P. W. equipment, flea market, Film reel (16mm) (Box 1.1)
      - Use copy, Optical disk (DVD) (Box 1.1U)
    - Interior and exterior views of Sargent's (Old Plant, New Haven), Film reel (16mm) (Box 1.2)
      - Use copy, Videotape (VHS) (Box 1.2U)
    - Development Program, Oak Street, slum demolition, city scenes prior to groundbreaking, Film reel (16mm) (Box 1.3)
      - Use copy, Videotape (VHS) (Box 1.3U)
    - Oak Street groundbreaking, Temple Street, Film reel (16mm) (Box 1.4)
      - Use copy, Optical disk (DVD) (Box 1.4U)
    - Oak Street groundbreaking, Temple Street, Film reel (16mm) (Reel 1.5)
      - Use copy, Optical disk (DVD) (Box 1.5U)
    - Campaign films general (Box 2)
    - Church Street South models, project development, Film reel (16mm) (Reel 2.1)
      - Use copy, Optical disk (DVD) (Box 2.1U)
    - Slums, Film reel (16 mm) (Box 2.2)
      - Duplicating master, Videotape (Betacam-SP) (Box 2.2D)
      - Use copy, Videotape (VHS) (Box 2.2U)
    - Slums, Film reel (16mm) (Box 2.3)
      - Duplicating master, Videotape (Betacam-SP) (Box 2.3D)
      - Use copy, Videotape (VHS) (Box 2.3U)
    - Progress in Renewal, Film reel (16m) (Box 2.4)
      - Duplicating master, Videotape (Betacam-SP) (Box 2.4D)
      - Use copy, Videotape (VHS) (Box 2.4U)
    - General (Box 3)
    - Crawford Manor construction, elderly citizen projects, Film reel (16mm) (Reel 3.1)
      - Use copy, Optical disk (DVD) (Box 3.1U)
    - Chapel Mall, Knights of Columbus site, 1965; Film reel (16mm) (Box 3.2)
      - Use copy, Optical disk (DVD) (Box 3.2U)
    - I-95 Connector, ribbon cutting, 1963; Film reel (16mm) (Box 3.3)
      - Use copy, Optical disk (DVD) (Box 3.3U)
    - A.C. Gilbert's, Macy's
      General
      The film is a duplicate of A. C. Gilbert Cut-Out, Redevelopment, Old Front Block (Box 3.5).
      - Use copy, Optical disk (DVD) (Box 3.4U)
    - A. C. Gilbert Cut-Out, Redevelopment, Old Front Block, 1963; Film reel (16mm) (Box 3.5)
      - Duplicating master, Videotape (Betacam-SP) (Box 3.5D)
      - Use copy, Videotape (VHS) (Box 3.5U)
    - TV campaign program, long version, 1963; Film reel (16 mm) (Box 3.6)
      - Use copy, Optical disk (DVD) (Box 3.6U)
    - Campain General (Box 4)
    - Downtown aerial, 1963 campaign, Film reel (16mm) (Reel 4.1)
      - Use copy, Videotape (VHS) (Box 4.1U)
    - Downtown, 1963 campaign, questions and answers section, Film reel (16mm) (Reel 4.2)
      - Use copy, Videotape (VHS) (Box 4.2U)
    - 1963 campaign, housing, Film reel (16mm) (Reel 4.3)
      - Use Copy, Videotape (VHS) (Box 4.3U)
  - Miscellaneous films (Box 5)
    1 2 3/4" reel, 2 3 1/2" reels, 9 10 1/2" reels
    Extent: 12 reels
  - Miscellaneous films (Box 6)
    - WNBC-TV, Connecticut Illustrated, "A City Reborn", 1966 (Box 6.1)
      - Duplicating master, Videotape (Betacam-SP) (Box 6.1D)
      - Use copy, Videotape (VHS) (Box 6.1U1)
      - Use copy, Videotape (VHS) (Box 6.1U2)
      - Use copy, Optical disk (DVD) (Box 6.1U3)
  - Miscellaneous tapes, Miscellaneous tapes include 102 reels of tape, 5 soundscriber discs, and 1 record.
    - Tapes, 3 600' reels, 9 1200' reels, 2 1800' reels, 6 misc. reels, 5 soundscriber discs 20 Extent: 5 discs (Box 7)
    - Tapes (Box 8)
      13 600' (or less) reels, 1 900' reel, 14 1200' reels, 2 1800' reels
      Extent: 30 reels
    - Tapes (Box 9)
      11 600' reels, 21 1200' reels
      Extent: 32 reels
    - Tapes (Box 10–11)
      3 1200', 1 1800', 16 misc., 1 record
      Extent: 20
  - Videotapes and film, 1961 (Box 12–14)
    Film in box 12 is titled "Mayor Lee, The Old and New New Haven." Film in box 13 is titled "Mayor Lee."
- Additional Material, 1985 July; Accession 1986-M-111
  - Correspondence
    - Chronological, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 1-7)
  - Alphabetical
    - A - Government Center, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 8-19)
    - Government Center - Police Foundation, 1978-1980 (Box 3, Folder 20-29)
    - Quinnipiac College - United Way, 1956-1980 (Box 4, Folder 30-38)
    - Yale - W, 1979-1980 (Box 5, Folder 39-40)
    - A - Boys Club, 1981-1984 (Box 5, Folder 41-47)
    - C - Connecticut Land Trust, 1981-1984 (Box 6, Folder 48-54)
    - Connecticut Law Enforcement Foundation - E, 1981-1984 (Box 7, Folder 55-64)
    - Easter Seals - Institute of Living, 1981-1984 (Box 8, Folder 65-71)
    - J - Lee, Richard C., 1981-1984 (Box 9, Folder 72-77)
    - Lee, Richard C. - Leevey, 1978-1984 (Box 10, Folder 78-84)
    - Legislature - M, 1981-1984 (Box 11, Folder 85-91)
    - McNamara - Rehab. Center, 1981-1984 (Box 12, Folder 92-101)
    - S - V, 1981-1984 (Box 13, Folder 102-109)
    - United Way - Yates, 1981-1984 (Box 14, Folder 110-117)
    - Appointment books, 1981-1984 (Box 15, Folder 118-125)
    - Expenses, 1981-1984 (Box 15, Folder 118-125)
    - New Haven Coliseum
    - New Haven Symphony Orchestra
    - Shubert Theater
    - Miscellaneous
- Additional Material, 1985-1987; Accession 1986-M-100
  Extent: .25' (1 box)
  Custodial History
  Received from Richard C. Lee, 1986 May 20 and 1987 Jun 19
  Also includes Accession 1987-M-090
  - Catholic Elementary School Study, New Haven, Connecticut, 1985 May (Box 1)
  - Cassette tapes, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Speeches, 1987 (Box 1)
- Additional Material, 1967-1986; Accession 1988-M-002
  Extent: .5 linear feet (1 box)
  Addition inventory by Nancy Lyon 1988 January
  Received from Richard C. Lee, 1987 July 1
  - Correspondence, 1967-1986 (Box 1)
  - Speeches, 1984-1986 (Box 1)
  - Citations for Richard C. Lee's honorary degrees, 1961-1982 (Box 1)
  - Knights of St. Patrick award, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Newspaper clipping, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Bibliography from Philip Singerman thesis, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Unidentified family history, undated (Box 1)
- Additional Material, 1984-1987; Accession 1988-M-042
  Received from Richard C. Lee, 1988 January 6
  - Photocopy of TLS from Thomas Bergin, 1984 December 21 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1987 March-November (Box 1)
  - Speeches, addresses, and eulogies, 1987 March-November (Box 1)
- Additional Material, 1988-1989; Accession 1988-M-084
  Extent: .25 linear feet (1 box)
  Received from: Richard C. Lee, 1988
  Also includes Accession 1989-M-006 & Accession 1989-M-052
  - Correspondence
    - Blanchard, Susan and her second grade students, 1988 April 13-20 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Brewster, Kingman, Mrs., 1989 January 4 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Carbone, Joseph, 1988 March 2 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Clement, Margie, 1988 November 9, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Leeney, Robert J., 1988 March 30 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Logue, Edward J., 1989 January 6 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Lyons, John M., 1988 February 14-23 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - McNamara, Julie, 1988 January 15 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Maier, Henry, 1988 March 30 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Mininberg, Ian, Mrs. (daughter of John W. Murphy, Mayor of New Haven, 1931-1945), 1988 October 22 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Rosenfeld, Harry, Mrs., 1988 February 22 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Siller, Robert, 1988 February 16-23 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Theobald, Michael, 1988 March 4 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Thim, John R., Mrs., 1988 December 9 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Whealon, John F., Archbishop of Hartford, 1988 March 22-28 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Speeches and Eulogies
    - Distinguised Service Award, Easter Seal Goodwill Industries, 1988 May 7 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Robert Leeney Dinner, 1988 May 29 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Statement to on Kingman Brewster's death, 1988 November 9 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Eulogy of John F. Kennedy on the twenty-fifth anniversary of his death, 1988 November 22 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Video cassette entitled "Dick Lee-A Man of New Haven,", 1988 May 7; 1 (Box 2)
- Additional Material, 1988-1989, undated; Accession 1990-M-055
  Addition inventory by Carol King 1990 Apr
  Received from: Richard C. Lee, 1990 Jan 4
  - Correspondence, 1989 February-Dec, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, memorandum of decision, and newspaper clippings relating to the Judicial Review Council's hearing on Judge Seymour Hendel, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Additional Material, 1957-1986, undated; Accession 1990-M-064
  Extent: 1.0 linear feet (1 box)
  Addition inventory by Carol King 1990 Jun
  Received from: Richard C. Lee, 1990 May 21
  - Correspondence, 1957, 1961, 1970, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1980s, 1980-1986, undated (Box 1, Folder 2-10)
  - Albertus Magnus College, 1985-1986 undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Banking legislation, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Box 22 Associates, 1980 October 14 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Connecticut Double Dutch Tournament, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Farrell, William F., Chief of Police, New Haven, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Greater New Haven Salute to Bart Giamatti, 1979 January 6 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Hospital of Saint Raphael, 1982, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Motley, Constance Baker, 1981, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Naming of the Ferry Street bridge, 1985 January (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - New Haven City Plan Commission, 1985 September 18 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - New Haven Colony Historical Society, 1980-1981, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1962, 1980-1986, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Programs for dedications, memorial services, graduations, 1982-1985 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Report, "The Extent, Distribution, and Causes of Poverty in New Haven," by the Special Commission on Poverty, 1983 July (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Reports, briefing papers, survey, 1972, 1977, 1981-1985, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Saint Patrick's Day Parade, photographs, 1982, undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Speeches and remarks by R.C. Lee, 1973, 1980, 1983-1985, undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Speeches and remarks by others, 1980, undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Miscellaneous papers, reprints, fact sheets, etc., 1980s (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Assorted periodicals and newsletters, 1980s (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Additional Material, 1960, 1980-1985, 1989-1990, n.d; Accession 1991-M-048
  Addition inventory by Carol King 1991 Jan
  Received from: Richard C. Lee, 1990 Dec 13
  - Correspondence, 1989 December 5-1990 September 26, undated (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - Writings
    - Memo to the New Haven Colony, Historical Society regarding a book donated by Richard C. Lee for its auction, 1990 April (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Speech for the Sons of the American Revolution, by Richard C. Lee, 1990 May 14 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - "The Death of World Politics," a working draft by Richard C. Lee, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Writings of others